Register of the Clovis E. Byers Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1946-1959.
  - "Some Aspects of Competitive Existence," speech, Ohio Society, Washington, D.C., 1959 January 31. (Folder 32: 10)
    Typescript. Includes holograph notes
  - "Today's Outlook for the Career Officer," address, West Point Association of New England, Boston, Massachusetts, 1959 March 21. (Folder 32: 11)
  - "Some Aspects of Competitive Existence," address, Ohio Society, New York City, 1959 April 6. (Folder 33: 12)
- Diaries and Appointment Books, 1918-1961.
  Appointment books, daily notes, diaries, and transcripts of diaries, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Appointment books
    - 1952 (Folder 32: 13)
    - 1957 (Folder 32: 14)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - 1959-1961 (Folder 33: 2)
  - Daily notes
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 33: 3)
    - 1959-1961 (Folder 33: 4)
  - Diaries
    - 1918-1924 (Folder 33: 5)
    - 1927-1930 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - 1931-1934 (Folder 34: 2)
    - 1935-1939 (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 35: 2)
    - 1942-1944 (Box-folder 36: 1)
    - 1945-1946 (Folder 36: 2)
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 36: 3)
    - 1951 and 1955-1957 (Box-folder 37: 1)
    - 1951 July ? December (Folder 37: 2)
    - 1952 January ? December (Folder 37: 3)
    - 1953 January - December (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - 1954 (Folder 38: 2)
  - Transcripts of diaries, 1946 January ? 1951 November (Folder 38: 3)
- Military File, 1925-1959. (Box 39)
  Bulletin, clippings, correspondence, day lists, fact sheet, financial records, lists, maps, memoranda, messages, note cards, orders, organizational charts, reports, schedule, statements, studies, subject file, and travel records relating to Clovis Byers' military career, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Bulletin, "Enemy-Tactics," X corps, number 10, Undated (Folder 39: 1)
  - Clippings
    - Invasion of the Philippines, 1945 (Folder 39: fA)
    - XVI Corps, 1952 (Folder 39: 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Folder 39: 3)
    - 1942-1947 (Folder 39: 4)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 39: 5)
  - Day lists, 1945-1947 (Folder 39: 6)
  - Fact sheet on guided missiles, 1958 (Folder 39: 7)
  - Financial records
    - General, 1939-1940 (Folder 39: 8)
    - Entertainment funds, 1947-1948 (Folder 39: 9)
    - Pay vouchers, 1942-1946 (Folder 39: 10)
    - Travel vouchers, 1949-1951. (Folder 39: 11)
      See also box 45 Illustrations
    - 4 illustrations including 1 depicting special car, U.S. Army, Jacksonville, Florida, undated; 1 depicting Allied Forces Corps Commander car, Saginaw, Texas? 1 depicting club lounge car, Red Bird, undated; and 1 depicting dining car, Savannah, Georgia (Folder 39: 12)
    - 1 postcard depicting military convoy, undated
    - 1 illustration depicting telephone terminal CF-1-B and experimental model of similar terminal, showing possible results of miniaturization program
  - Lists
    - Security classified papers, undated (Folder 39: 13)
    - Joint committee, undated. (Folder 39: 14)
      Includes lists of sub-committees, United States and Japanese personnel, and list of representatives from the press and agricultural sector
    - Intelligence summaries on individuals in Japan issued by the Office of the Chief of Counter Intelligence, 1946 (Folder 39: 15)
      Includes note cards with the same information and a letter from Douglas MacArthur to Robert Eichelberger(?), 1942 December 13
    - Important papers, 1946 (Folder 39: 16)
    - Instructions issued by the Deputy Chief of Staff, Pacific Office, for personnel attending surrender ceremony, 1945 September 2, and those issued by the Office of the Commanding General to be presented to the Commanding General, First Japanese General Army, 1945 September 4 (Folder 39: 17)
    - Names of congressmen, correspondents, commanders, and staffs, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - Roster of officers holding a specified rank, 1946 August 7 (Folder 40: 2)
    - General officers and other visitors invited to the armor conference, Fort Knox, Kentucky, 1955 January 25 (Folder 40: 3)
  - Maps, 1946 (Folder 40: 4)
  - Memoranda
    - Undated (Folder 40: 5)
    - 1931-1958 (Folder 40: 6)
  - Messages
    - Undated (Folder 40: 7)
    - 1942-1952 (Folder 40: 8)
  - Note cards and notes, 1947 and undated (Folder 40: 9)
  - Orders
    - 1934 April 13 - 1937 March 20 (Folder 40: 10)
    - 1937 April 1 ? 1939 April 5 (Folder 40: 11)
    - 1939 April 11 ? 1941 December 11 (Folder 40: 12)
    - 1942 February 28 ? 1943 November 4 (Folder 40: 13)
    - 1944 January 15 ? 1945 December 4 (Folder-box 41: 1)
    - 1946 January 15 ? 1949 December 29 (Folder 41: 2)
    - 1948 January 24 ? 1950 October 24 (Folder 41: 3)
    - 1951 June 21 ? 1952 October 30 (Folder 41: 4)
    - 1956 February 21 ? 1959 April 14 (Folder 41: 5)
    - 1957 April 12 ? September 18 (Folder 41: 6)
  - Organizational charts for Third Army, Seventh Army, Philippines-Ryukyus Command, Far East Command, and political and administrative agencies in Japan officially accredited by or otherwise related to SCAP, 1947. (Folder 41: 7)
    Includes a proposed chart for Automatic Weapons Battery, Airborne Antiaircraft Battalion, undated
  - Personal file, 1934-1958. (Folder 41: 8-11)
    Includes materials relating to relocation
  - Press releases
    - Undated (Folder 41: 12)
    - 1958 (Folder 41: 13)
  - Reports
    - Mindoro-Marinduque report, 1945 (Folder 41: 14)
    - Efficiency reports on general officers, 1948 (Folder 41: 15)
    - "Reports of the Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting of the National Society Magna Charta Dames,", 1950 (Folder 41: 16)
    - X Corps periodic personnel reports, 1951 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - Reports from Europe, 1957-1959 (Folder 42: 2-4)
  - Schedule, 1942-1959 (Folder 42: 5)
  - Statements, 1955-1958. (Box-folder 43: 1)
    A descriptive statement of the organization, functions, and procedures of the Operations Coordinating Board (OCB), 1955, and statement of the Secretary of Defense, Neil McElroy, regarding appropriations on the fiscal year 1959 budget, 1958
  - Studies
    - Undated. (Folder 43: 2)
      A comparative study of American, French, German, English, Japanese, Italian, and Russian doctrines on the value of a permanent corps organization for cavalry; the horse, arms, and equipment of the American cavalry trooper compared with those of England, France, Germany, and Spain; development of airborne forces; and sociological study of diseases in XVI Corps
    - 1925-1939. (Folder 43: 3)
      Includes studies of equipment of the British cavalry trooper; possible routes of march between El Paso, Texas, and Columbus, New Mexico; attacks in converging directions; research data, and related materials
    - 1948. (Folder 43: 4)
      Airborne Division's assessment of aircraft loading characteristics, requirements for airdromes and aircraft, and current airborne developments
  - Subject file
    - American Assembly, Arden House, Columbia University, New York, 1958 (Folder 43: 5)
    - Army War College, 1950 (Folder 43: 6)
    - Australia--Eleanor Roosevelt's trip, 1943 (Folder 43: 7-8)
    - Fox River Valley Seminar on United States foreign policy, University of Wisconsin, Wisconsin, 1958 May 16-18. (Folder 43: 9)
      Includes holograph notes about conference sessions, list of participants, and papers by others, including Henry Kissinger and Dean Acheson
    - Indo-China, 1957 (Folder 43: 10)
    - MacKechnie, A. R., 1943 (Folder 43: 11)
    - NATO Defense College (Box 44)
      - Undated (Folder 44: 1-5)
      - 1955-1957 (Folder 44: 6-11)
      - 1957-1959 (Box-folder 45: 1-4)
    - Sheridan, John Edward, 1946 (Folder 45: 5)
  - Travel records.
    See also box 39 for travel vouchers
    - General, 1947-1954. (Folder 45: 6-8)
      Includes itineraries and travel orders
    - Trips.
      Includes miscellaneous materials
      - Alumni day trip to Ohio State University, 1956 (Folder 45: 9)
      - Germany, 1956-1957 (Folder 45: 10)
      - Japan, 1945-1947. (Folder 45: 11-12)
        See also box 30 for Byers' correspondence with his family while stationed in Japan and box 47 for photocopies of documents relating to the surrender of Japan
      - Korea, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 46: 1)
      - London, 1957. (Folder 46: 2)
        See also folders 4-5
      - Naples, 1952-1953. (Folder 46: 3)
        See also folder 7
      - Northern Europe, 1955-1957. (Folder 46: 4-5)
        See also folder 2
      - Portugal, 1957 (Folder 46: 6)
      - Southern Europe, 1956-1957. (Folder 46: 7)
        See also folder 3
      - Turkey, 1953 (Folder 46: 8)
  - Writings by others, 1947-1958 (Folder 46: 9)
  - Miscellany, 1945-1948 (Folder 46: 10)
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1944-1952 (Box 46)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government. Includes some interfiled records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover
  - 2011 July release of records, 1944-1952 (Folder 46: 11)
    Letters, cables and memos. Most correspondents are members of the U.S. Army
- Oversize Materials, 1945. (Box 47)
  Photocopies of the documents relating to the surrender of Japan
  - Photocopies of materials relating to surrender of Japan.
    See also boxes 30 and 45
- Photographs, 1922-1954.
  Photographic and contact prints, illustrations, and albums, depicting Clovis Byers, his family, other army officers, and places he was assigned to for his military duties
  - Albums
    - Clippings relating to the invasion of Japan, 1945 (Folder fA)
    - Tour of duty in the Pacific and Japan, 1942-1946 (Folder fB)
    - Tour of duty in Japan, 1946-1949 (Folder fC)
    - Tour of duty in Korea, 1951 (Folder fD)
    - Tour of duty in Japan, 1951-1952 (Folder fE)
    - Tour of duty of duty in Japan and Europe, 1952-1954 (Folder fF)
    - Rockhampton, Australia, area, 1943 (Folder fG)
  - Loose photographs
    - The Pacific, Japan, and Korea, undated (Folder H)
    - 7 prints of British, German, and Spanish cavalry, circa 1925 (Folder I)
    - 6 oversize prints of Byers, undated (Folder mJ)
    - 2 oversize prints depicting Byers with other officers of the 4th U.S. Cavalry at Fort McIntosh, Texas, January 1922; and with the first-year class, Command and General Staff School, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, 1934-1935 (Folder m*K)
    - 5 negatives and 2 contact prints depicting unidentified individuals in an outdoor setting, undated (Box-folder 48: 1)
    - 6 prints including 3 depicting Byers and other unidentified army officers, 1 depicting an open box, 2 depicting moving trains, undated (Folder 48: 2)
    - 14 prints, including 5 illustrations depicting helicopter truck, glider cargo capacities, aircraft load and range characteristics, and the squad boxes, undated; and 9 prints depicting aircraft, parachute, gliders, and helicopters (Folder 48: 3)
    - 9 prints including 8 depicting Byers, Mrs. Byers, and their son; and 1 depicting 8 month old Glen Gray, Jr., undated (Folder 48: 4)
    - 7 prints including 1 depicting Clovis Byers and Alden K. Sibley during his visit to the U.S. Army Engineer Division, New England, undated; 1 depicting the Watson children wishing a happy holiday season, undated; 2 prints depicting 2 Flak Boas, 1944 March 22; 2 prints depicting Byers sent to him to wish a happy Easter from Yokohama, Japan, 1947; and 1 print depicting Joseph Kormylo. Fort Gulick, Canal Zone, 1950 April (Folder 48: 5)
    - 3 prints including 2 depicting a dog outside a house, 1952 May 29, and 1 commemorative photograph of the Japanese Imperial family, 1952 September 16 (Folder 48: 6)
- 2 Aug 1875 full retreat dress parade sound recording, undated.; 1 sound tape reel (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
  This is a sound recording of a full retreat dress parade of 2 Aug 1875 held at Fort Davis in Texas. It was made for the National Park Service and Fort Davis Historical Site.
  Use access copy number: 64016_a_0008860
- Motion Picture, undated. (Film-shelf Film shelf)
  One 16mm film reel